classifieds.co.uk 2012-11-04

# Classifieds.co.uk - Classified ads

Effective Date: Wednesday 15th September 2010

_Generally Classifieds.co.uk ("Site" or "we", "our" or "us") will not collect, store, use ordisclose any data collected with an intention to identify and/or contact a person such as: name, address, telephone number or e-mail address (hereinafter "PII") except in very specific instances, for example, when you provide PII through registering on the Site and placing an advert on the Site or as set forth in this Privacy Policy. Whenever we collect such PII, it will be governed by this Privacy Policy._

This service is provided by Classifieds.co.uk which is operated by Freeads Classifieds Ltd. For us, privacy is a top priority and we provide this Privacy Policy to outline our practices and procedures with respect to information collection and use to enable you to make an informed decision about sharing information with us. 

**What does this Privacy Policy cover?**

This Privacy Policy applies to collection, use, storage and disclosure of information by us. 

Please be aware that, as part of the service provided by this Site, we may provide links to websites operated by third parties. We are not responsible for the information collection or privacy practices or the content of those third party Web sites or applications. You should check the applicable privacy policies of such third-party Web sites or applications to determine how they handle any information they collect from you. 

**What information do we collect and how is it used? Do we disclose information to third parties?**

We may collect any or all of the following three types of information: (i) traffic or clickstream data, (ii) non-personally identifiable information (for example: IP address, browser types, operating systems, domain names, access dates and times, referring website addresses, online transactions and browsing and search activity) ("Non-PII"), and/or (iii) PII in the instances as set forth in this Privacy Policy. Our collection and use of each type of data is described below, as well as the ways (if any) in which the data may be shared with third parties or subsidiaries or affiliates of Classifieds.co.uk. Classifieds.co.uk may use third party vendors to help us operate our business and this Site or administer activities on our behalf. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes. Any third-party vendor so used has agreed to protect the confidentiality of information provided by Classifieds.co.uk and adhere to the provisions in this privacy policy. 

Classifieds.co.uk may share non PII (including information that has been enhanced with information from other sources) with co-branded partners, advertisers, third party marketers, our affiliated entities for their online and/or offline marketing programs or in connection with the sale, merger, consolidation, change in control, transfer of substantial asset, reorganization or liquidation of any Classifieds.co.uk division. 

Classifieds.co.uk may release account and any other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to respond to a subpoena or otherwise comply with the law; enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Classifieds.co.uk or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection. 

**a) Traffic or Clickstream Data ("Clickstream Data").**

Clickstream Data consists of traffic and usage data that is not personally identifiable. We do not supplement or combine Clickstream Data with any PII. We may share Clickstream Data we collect with certain selected third parties and Freeads Classifieds Ltd Entities, but only in anonymous form. Notwithstanding the foregoing, such third parties and Freeads Classifieds Ltd Entities may combine such Clickstream Data with any PII that you choose to give to such third parties or Freeads Classifieds Ltd Entities when registering with their websites. We collect Clickstream Data regarding use of our services by observing browser functions and the files (pages) you access. For example, our servers collect information about the site to which you may redirect to in order to enable us to calculate and receive payments from our business partners. In addition, we may use Clickstream Data to better design our services. Within the company and with respect to online behavioural advertising, certain affiliated companies may use non-personally identifiable information (which may or may not include click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) collected during your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioural advertising practice and/or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). 

**(b) Non-Personally Identifiable Information.**

For each visitor to our website, our Web server automatically recognizes only the visitor's IP address. We use your IP address to administer our website. Upon visiting our website, we assign each visitor a unique ID that is used to track visitor traffic patterns within our website. We also collect aggregate and user-specific information on the pages that visitors access or visit. We reserve the right to retain all website traffic reporting data as long as may be reasonably necessary for accounting and auditing purposes. As part of our on-going efforts to ensure the best possible experience for all users of the Site, we may use log files, web beacons and cookies to collect Non-PII from the Site, browsers, advertisers and third-party sites. "Log files" track actions occurring on the Site and collect data including: your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, click data and types of advertisements viewed. Image requests or ("web beacons") can transmit information used to track your data, which may include the navigation of a website or collection of sites, the completion of transactions, submittal of applications and browsing behaviour. This information is written to cookies."Cookies" are files that are stored on your Internet enabled device (which includes your computer, BlackBerry or other PDA). Cookies are used to improve the experience web users have when they see web advertisements and ensure that when a web user clicks on an advertisement, they are sent to the correct click-through destination. We may use Cookies for purposes which may include, without limitation, to estimate the total reach of any of our advertisers, how frequently you return to the Site, as well as to streamline experiences of users of our Site. Cookies are also an anonymous way to survey how we are doing and to look for ways to improve our services. All information collected by Cookies, Web beacons and Log files are Non-PII. 

There are two classes of Cookies based on how long they remain on your system: (i) "Session Cookies" may be used only during your visit to the Site and are erased once you close your browser, and (ii) "Persistent Cookies" (if applicable) remain on your browser for one (1) year from your last visit to the Site and enable us to remember you on subsequent visits to the Site and provide more relevant content to you on such Site. 

There are many misconceptions about Cookies, some of which we will try to address in this policy. Cookies cannot erase your hard drive or otherwise damage your computer and do not tell us an e-mail address or any other PII. We do not and cannot use Cookies or web beacons to retrieve PII from your computer. 

A useful resource on understanding Cookies may be found at [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

We also use this information for internal business purposes, such as aggregating the data to help us to create a profile of Classifieds.co.uk visitors, as a whole, so that we can: a) build a better understanding of our users and enhance the services we offer, and b) attract advertisers to spend money on Classifieds.co.uk, thus enabling our free price comparison service to operate. 

**(c) Third Party Advertising.**

We have relationships with third-party advertising companies to drive traffic to and to serve ads on our Site. We share Clickstream Data and Non-PII with such advertising companies. Such companies may also collect non-personally identifiable information through the use of Cookies and other technology and any personally identifiable information you may choose to give in registering and transacting with any website linked to such ads. Although we choose our business partners and clients carefully, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policies of these third-party advertisers to determine how they handle any information they collect from you. 

**(d) Contact Information or Personally Identifying Information.**

Classifieds.co.uk does not automatically collect any personal information about you. We do collect PII, including but not limited to your name, e-mail address, primary phone number, secondary phone number, post code through membership registration in order to place an ad or newsletter sign-up requests. . We have access to your PII after such PII has been submitted to us where for example (i) you provide us with personal and corporate information, such as name, address, email address and other account information, in order to be able to access and use our services, (ii) you provide information when you send us inquiries relating to our services or in relation to this Privacy Policy, (iii) you become a registered user of our Site, (iv) you subscribe to any of our newsletters, (v) you contact us by submitting a comment, problem, or request for information, for example if you report a problem with our site. 

PII provided in connection with problems, comments or requests is used only to respond to those problems, comments or requests. This information is not stored or used in connection with Clickstream Data and is provided to a third party only as necessary to respond to the comment, problem or request or as required by law or court order. 

Please note that it is not necessary for you to become a member in order to use many of the features on Classifieds.co.uk. A non-member can easily see classified ads, perform searches and take advantage of many other useful features on the site. 

Classifieds.co.uk also operates a free e-newsletter service - the Update - to help you keep up-to-date with the best deals, contests and news. This is an opt-in service so, as a member, you will receive the newsletter. To unsubscribe simply send an e-mail to [info@classifieds.co.uk](mailto:info@classifieds.co.uk) and include your e-mail address. 

The reason that we ask for this PII is to provide you with information that you may request, to customize your experience on the Site, and to contact you when necessary in connection with any promotions you participate in. 

Finally, from time to time, but only with your permission, we may provide your PII to selected third parties who wish to participate in special promotions offered in conjunction with us. 

**Do we collect personally identifying information from or about children?**

We use reasonable efforts not to collect, use or disclose PII from children under the age of 13. The services are not targeted at children, and children aged 13 and under may not register for any portions of the services that require registration. If you believe your child has provided us with any PII data by registering on our Site, please specify this issue and email us at [support@classifieds.co.uk](mailto:support@classifieds.co.uk). 

**How is my data processed?**

We may disclose data to other entities within the EU belonging to the Freeads Classifieds Ltd and to third parties located in the EU to the extent that such disclosure is not incompatible with the purposes for which data are collected as mentioned above, but only that they provide adequate privacy protection. 

You acknowledge that Classifieds.co.uk and its affiliate entities operate in the United States and the European Union and agree to (i) permit Classifieds.co.uk to transmit and use your User information anywhere necessary, including across international boundaries, to affect the services and transactions provided by this Site; and (ii) that such use by us shall be subject to the Terms stated in this Privacy Policy and our [Terms of Use](http://www.classifieds.co.uk/info/terms). 

**Do I have choices?**

The Cookies we use do not have an "opt-out" option, yet you still have the option of blocking the use of cookies by changing a setting in your Internet browser. Please see your browser supplier's website for details on how to do this. 

If you have multiple internet browsers or users on the same computer, you will need to perform the opt-out operation for each browser and/or user. If you or your privacy software blocks the use of cookies, you will need to repeat the opt-out operation for each browser and/or user by changing a setting in your Internet browser. Alternatively, most internet browsers and browser add-ons allow you to adjust their settings to allow you to automatically refuse Cookies either generally or from specific sites. To adjust these settings, we suggest that you contact the supplier of you browser and browser add-ons for more information. 

Please note that the implementation of browser settings that refuse all cookies will affect our ability to provide you content and advertisements that will more effectively match your interests and may prevent us from controlling the frequency with which you may view any particular advertisement. "Session Cookies" are used only during your visit to the Site and are erased once you close your browser. 

We may need to share information you have supplied with third parties in limited circumstances for legal compliance, to prevent fraud or imminent harm, to ensure security, or in case of a transfer of ownership of the company. We do not collect or process any sensitive data such as data about health or similarly sensitive matters. 

If at any time you no longer wish to receive e-newsletters from Classifieds.co.uk, you may "unsubscribe" by sending an email to [support@classifieds.co.uk](mailto:support@classifieds.co.uk) or by using the unsubscribe option within the email. In compliance with the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003, you will be removed entirely from our email list and will no longer receive e-newsletters from us. If you have registered or submitted PII under more than one email account, you must submit separate unsubscribe requests from each account. 

**Is data stored by us secure?**

We take appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect your personal data. We employ industry standard security measures to ensure the security of all data. While we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. You acknowledge and assume this risk when communicating with us. 

**How can I learn about changes to this privacy policy?**

We may find it necessary or be legally obligated to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of the information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. Your continued usage of this site after such notice shall constitute acceptance of any such changes. 

We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy whenever you use this Site to make sure you understand how your information will be used. 

**Limitation of Liability, Third Party Information & Language**

YOU UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT ANY DISPUTE OVER PRIVACY IS SUBJECT TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND OUR TERMS AND CONDITIONS (INCLUDING LIMITATIONS ON DAMAGES, AND ARBITRATION OF DISPUTES). YOU AGREE THAT CLASSIFIEDS.CO.UK'S LIABILITY FOR ANY BREACH OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY SHALL BE LIMITED TO THE VALUE OF THE TRANSACTIONS OR SERVICES PROVIDED TO YOU BY CLASSIFIEDS.CO.UK TO THE EXTENT SUCH CLAIM IS NOT OTHERWISE BARRED BY OUR TERMS AND CONDITIONS. NOTHING IN THIS AGREEMENT LIMITS OR EXCLUDES EITHER PARTY'S LIABILITY FOR FRAUD OR FOR NEGLIGENCE CAUSING DEATH OR PERSONAL INJURY. 

You also agree that you have provided notice to, and obtained consent from, any third party individuals whose personal data you supply to Classifieds.co.uk with regard to: (a) the purposes for which such third party's data has been collected; (b) the intended recipients or categories of recipients of the third party's personal data; (c) which of the third party's data are obligatory and which data, if any, are voluntary; and (d) how the third party can access and, if necessary, rectify the data held about them. 

**How do I find out more about our information practices?**

If you have any questions about anything in this Privacy Policy, please contact us as follows: 

  * E-Mail: [support@classifieds.co.uk](mailto:support@classifieds.co.uk)
  * Classifieds.co.uk is operated by Freeads Classifieds Ltd.
  * Registered in England and Wales, No. 04438153.

  * Freeads Classifieds Ltd.
  * Westmead House
  * Westmead
  * Farnborough
  * Hampshire
  * GU14 7LP

  * Registered office:
  * 15 Bolton Street,
  * Mayfair,
  * London,
  * W1Y 8AR
